Charles Wharton Stork Papers
Charles Wharton Stork Papers
1876-1970
Stork, Charles Wharton, 1881-
30 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet, playwright, novelist, editor of Contemporary Verse, 1917-1925, translator of Scandinavian verse, educator. Collection includes correspondence, mostly in connection with Contemporary Verse; and writings, in manuscript and published versions, including essays, novels, plays, and poems; photographs; and extensive family and literary correspondence (1899-1970).
146328
Biographical History
Charles Wharton Stork was an American author, a graduate of Haverford and of Harvard, and taught in the Department of English at the University of Pennsylvania. Stork produced poems, plays, novels, and translations of Scandinavian verse, and was the editor of Contemporary Verse from 1917-1925.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Charles Wharton Stork Papers consist of manuscripts, published material, legal papers such as wills and deeds, clippings, scrapbooks, photographs and correspondence. The vast majority of the collection consists of writings, both manuscript and unpublished. The inventory below includes a small original accession and a substantially larger 1993 accession; there are also smaller additions that do not appear on this finding aid. The collection has not been processed and remains in original order; following is a box list only.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has not been processed and remains in original order. The original accession contains BOTH manuscripts and published material; these items are listed separately below but are intermingled in the boxes. Note that box numbering restarts with the 1993 accession so box numbers are not unique; please specify accession and box number when requesting material.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- American Fiction; Stork, Charles Wharton, 1881- Archives.; Contemporary verse.; Authors, American.; Dramatists, American.; Little magazines -- United States.; Novelists, American.; Periodical editors -- United States.; Poetry -- Periodicals.; Poetry, Modern -- 20th century.; Poets, American.; Women poets, American.; United States -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Essays.; Manuscripts (document genre); Photographs.; Poems.; Translations.; Editors.; Educators.; Novelists.; Playwrights.; Poets.; Translators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Writings (original accession)
  - Manuscripts
    See Published material below for a list of books contained in Boxes 1-7.
    - Alcibiades: A play of Athens in the Great Age, typescript (Box 1)
    - "T.S. Eliot Revises His Creed", typescript, 20 pp. (Box 1)
    - The Egoist, typescript, 180 pp. (Box 2)
    - Falstaff on Broadway, typescript carbon, 66 pp. (Box 2)
    - Walt: The Pageant of an American, typescript, 113 pp. (Box 2)
    - Early Reflections of Ezra Pound, typescript, 18 pp. (Box 3)
    - "Recalling a Breton Sailor", typescript, 4 pp. (Box 4)
    - "A Visit to Pandit Nehru", typescript, 4 pp. (Box 4)
    - "The Western Lake, Hangchow", typescript, 3ppp. (Box 4)
    - "Coffee With Sibelius", typescript, 4 pp. (Box 4)
    - Published material, See Published material below for a listing of Box 5 contents. (Box 5)
    - "Personal Impressions of Bernard Shaw", typescript, 16 pp. (Box 6)
    - "The Later Yeats Revisited", typescript, 9 pp. (Box 6)
    - "Three Variations", typescript, 8 pp. (Box 6)
    - "When You Go to Oxford", typescript, 6 pp. (Box 6)
    - "The Homebreaker", typescript, 37 pp. (Box 6)
    - "Of Food and Eating", typescript, 13 pp. (Box 6)
    - "The Ball of Twine", typescript, 17 pp. (Box 6)
    - Alcibiades, Galleys. (Box 7)
  - Published works
    See Manuscripts above for a list of manuscripts contained in Boxes 1-7.
    - The Poetic Year for 1916: A critical Anthology by William Stanley Braithwaite. CWS poem included. (Box 1)
    - Modern Swedish Masterpieces. New York: E.P. Dutton Co., 1923 (Box 1)
    - The Dragon and the Foreign Devils by Johan Gunnar Andersson. translated by CWS. Boston: Little, Brown and Co.: 1928 (Box 1)
    - William Rowley. Philadelphia: Publications of the University of Pennsylvania, 1910 (Box 1)
    - "A Vision of Misjudgment" Brochure issued at New York by The Fine Editions Press: 1958 (Box 1)
    - "Verse translation from the Modern Scandinavian," Scandinavian Studies XX, No. 2 (May, 1948) (Box 2)
    - Second Contemporary Verse Anthology, edited by CWS. New York: E.P. Dutton, 1923 (Box 3)
    - The Golden Year: The Poetry Society of America Anthology (1910-1960). New York; The Fine Editions Press, 1960. poem of CWS included. (Box 3)
    - Hearts and Voices. Boston: Christopher Publishing House, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Navpac. New York: Bookman Associates, 1952 (Box 3)
    - Gustaf Froding: Selected poems. translated by CWS. New York: The Macmillan Co., 1916 (Box 4)
    - Anthology of Norwegian Lyrics. translated by CWS, Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1942 (Box 4)
    - The Lyrical poems of Hugo Von Hofmannsthal. translated by CWS. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1918 (Box 4)
    - Day Dreams of Greece. Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott Co. (19U) (Box 4)
    - Anthology of Swedish Lyrics (1750-1915) translated by CWS. New York: American Scandinavian Foundation, 1917 (Box 4)
    - Sea and Bay: A poem of New England. New York John Lane Co., 1916 (Box 4)
    - On Board Old Ironsides (1812-1815). Mill Valley: The Wings Press (Box 4)
    - Arcadia Borealis: Selected poems of Erik Axel Karlfeldt, translated by CWS. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press, 1938 (Box 4)
    - Sweden's Laureate: Selected poems of Verner von Heidenstam. translated by CWS. New Haven: Yale University Press. 1919 (Box 4)
    - The Charles Men by Verner von Heidenstam, translated by CWS. New York: American-Scandinavian Foundation, 1961 (Box 5)
    - Sweden's Best Stories: An Introduction to Swedish Fiction. translated by CWS. New York: W. W. Norton, 192 (Box 5)
    - Contemporary Verse Anthology 1916-1920, Edited by CWS. New York: E.P. Dutton, 1920 (Box 5)
    - The Tales of Ensign Stal by Johan Ludwig Runeberg. translated by CWS. New York: The American-Scandinavian Foundation; 1960 (Box 5)
    - The Motherless by Bengt Berg. translated by CWS. Garden City, Doubleday, Page and Co., 1924 (Box 5)
    - Martin Brick's Youth by Hjalmar Soderberg. translated by CWS. New York: Harper and Brothers: 1920 (Box 5)
    - I Sit Alone by Waldemar Ager. translated by CWS. New York: Harper and Brothers, 1931 (Box 5)
    - A Second Book of Danish Verse, translated by CWS, Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1947 (Box 5)
    - Alcibiades. Syracuse: Syracuse University Press, 1967 (Box 6)
- Writings (1993 accession)
  - A Daughter of Boston, typescript (Box 1)
  - Alcibiades, typescript (Box 1)
  - Ninon, typescript (Box 1)
  - Ninon, typescript (Box 1)
  - The Connoisseur, typescript (Box 1)
  - Semele, original typescript (Box 1)
  - Semele, carbon typescript (Box 1)
  - The Egotist, carbon (Box 1)
  - In Earthen Vessels, carbon fragment (Box 1)
  - Renee, typescript (Box 1)
  - Drawbacks, draft (Box 1)
  - Falstaff on Broadway, carbon copy (Box 1)
  - Tristan the Nero, typescript (Box 1)
  - The Idiot, original typescript (Box 1)
  - Whispered in the Afternoon (Box 1)
  - Interdependence (Manche Frelich) (Box 1)
  - The Two, typescript poems (Box 1)
  - Misc. fragments (Box 1)
  - Misc. poems (Box 1)
  - The Poetry of Verner Von Heidenstam, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Aphorisms on Portraiture, typescript (Box 1)
  - Poetry Reviews, typescript (Box 1)
  - How a poem Won a Friend, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Memories of England, typescript title page, contents page, acknowledgements (Box 1)
  - The Attack on the "Speedomania", typescript essay (Box 1)
  - A Voice from the Crowd, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Take What the Earth Can Offer, poem (Box 1)
  - Misc. poems and Christmas Cards (Box 1)
  - National Solidarity: A Doubtful Idea, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Early Recollections of Ezra Pound, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Notebook containing misc. essays and notes (Box 1)
  - R.L.S. Comes Britain's Parnassus and The Mermaid Tavern poem (Box 1)
  - Misc. fragments (Box 1)
  - King Ardamenes, typescript poems (Box 1)
  - Article on ??, holograph essay (Box 1)
  - The German Spirit, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Robert Browning: How to Know Him, holograph essay (Box 1)
  - Personal Memories of Owen Wister, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - A Keats-Shelley Complex, holograph poem (Box 1)
  - Unidentified ms. fragment (Box 1)
  - The Words Complain to the Modern Poets, poem (Box 1)
  - Israel's Christmases, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Misc. fragments (Box 1)
  - The writing of Social Poetry, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The Chinaman, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The New Spirit of American Poetry, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The Influence of the Popular Ballad on Wordsworth and Coleridge, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Recalling a Breton Sailor, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - A Petal on a Lonely Path, holograph essay (Box 1)
  - Fragment (Box 1)
  - Reading Aloud: An Art and a Solace, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Untitled misc. fragment (Box 1)
  - The New Spirit in American Poetry, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The Open Secret, poetry (Box 1)
  - Hospital Exigencies and Amenities, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Verner Von Heidenstam: Swedish Poet and Novelist, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The Something Else, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Of Food and Eating, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Three Variations, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Notes on Lit. Course (Box 1)
  - Nehru. A Personal Impression, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Coffee with Sibelius, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Nehru and Breton Sailor (Box 1)
  - Music in a Crisis, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Marta af Sillen: Personal Memories of a Modern Swedish Author, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Exam and Lecture for a Lit. Course (Box 1)
  - What is Originality?, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Hospital Exigencies and Amenities, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Reading for Exercise, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The Factories with Other Lyrics, typescript poem (Box 1)
  - A Voice from the Crowd, holograph essay (Box 1)
  - Personal Impressions of Bernard Shaw, typescript essay and pub. copy (Box 1)
  - John Hall Wheelock, American Poet, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The Natural Thing, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The German Spirit, holograph essay (Box 1)
  - Misc. essays, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Misc. fragments (Box 1)
  - Saving Selma, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The Western Lake, Hangchow, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Three Variations on a Theme in the Key of I Major, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The Code of Munich, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Under the Lion's Paw, typescript play (Box 1)
  - Addresses of Honorable Carl J. Hambro, pamphlet (Box 1)
  - Fragment of a play, holograph (Box 1)
  - Misc. poems (Box 1)
  - Misc. poems and fragments (Box 1)
  - It Passes in a Moment, musical score words by CWS (Box 1)
  - On the Trail of a Hero, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Jane Pratt: Counselor at Love, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - No Place for Tourists from "Christian Science Monitor", clipping (Box 1)
  - Here's Happy Days, Autobiography title page and acknowledgements (Box 1)
  - The Educated American from the Angle of a Writer, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Toward the Inner Technic of Poetry, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Misc. fragments (Box 1)
  - The Great and Near Great, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The Forgotten Word, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - AB: A Modern American Comedy in Three Acts, typescript play (Box 1)
  - AB: A Modern American Comedy in Three Acts, typescript play (Box 1)
  - The Falcon, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Competition: A Post Emersonian Ramble, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - What it is All About, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Personal Habits, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Goethe and Walt Whitman: A Study in Poetic Evolution, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Meeting in Hong Kong, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Misc. poems by Jo Johnson (Box 1)
  - Far-Borne Echoes, typescript poem (Box 1)
  - Ninon, holograph review (Box 1)
  - Crecento, printed play by Hans Heinz Ewers (Box 1)
  - The Meeting of Christ and Pan, typescript collection of poems (Box 1)
  - AB: A Modern American Comedy in Three Acts, holograph play (Box 1)
  - Bound book containing misc. essays and poems (Box 1)
  - Old and New Delhi, typescript poem (Box 1)
  - Misc. fragments (Box 1)
  - Being Estelle, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Songs of Joy, typescript poems (Box 1)
  - Hangchow, typescript poems (Box 1)
  - Misc. poems, typescript (Box 1)
  - Escapism, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The Ash-Can School of Literature, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - The Eagle and the Sun, typescript essay (Box 1)
  - Misc. poems and fragments (Box 1)
  - Misc. poems (Box 1)
  - Daft Andy: An Ulster Ballad, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - Prescription: One Wife - To be Taken Seriously, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - The Falcon, typescript story (Box 2)
  - New Light on Gustaf Fröding, typescript review (Box 2)
  - The Stars Above, typescript play (Box 2)
  - The Motherless by Bengt Berg, translation by CWS typescript ms. (Box 2)
  - The Motherless by Bengt Berg, translation by CWS holograph ms. (Box 2)
  - Jimmie Jones in Heaven, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - A Spot on a Dress, typescript story (Box 2)
  - Misc. poems and fragments (Box 2)
  - Joseph Hergesheimer, The New American Novelist, typescript review (Box 2)
  - The New Spirit in American Poetry, holograph ms. (Box 2)
  - Frederick W. Taylor and Scientific Management, holograph essay (Box 2)
  - Women in American Poetry Today, holograph and typescript essays (Box 2)
  - The World is too Much for Us Wm. Wordsworth, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - Dear Lord, That Ever Carest by F.M. Fronzen, Translation by CWS poem (Box 2)
  - Saul and David by Gustaf Fröding, translation by CWS typescript poem (Box 2)
  - Recent Volumes of Verse, typescript and holograph reviews (Box 2)
  - To the One Who Has Suffered and Of a Dedication, typescript poems (Box 2)
  - Misc. poems (Box 2)
  - Misc. poems (Box 2)
  - Misc. poems and Reviews (Box 2)
  - Misc. poems and fragments (Box 2)
  - Fragment of Galley Proof (Box 2)
  - New Light on Gustaf Fröding, holograph review (Box 2)
  - Childhood Friends by Verner Von Heidenstam, translation by CWS; typescript poem (Box 2)
  - The Man in Front of Me, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - The Concord of Learning, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - The Death of Orpheus, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - The Other Cheek, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - Misc. fragments (Box 2)
  - Ulysses and the Sirens, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - Laughter: An Ode, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - Misc. poems by Hoffmansthal, typescript poems (Box 2)
  - Misc. poems and fragments (Box 2)
  - The Lyrical poems of Hugo Von Hoffmansthal, translation by CWS typescript – poems (Box 2)
  - Misc. poems (Box 2)
  - Verse translation from the Modern Scandinavian, typescript essay (Box 2)
  - Franz Von Pausinger, typescript essay (Box 2)
  - Misc. poems (Box 2)
  - The Key of Song, typescript poem – 2 copies (Box 2)
  - The Forest of Tears, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - The Wound of Joy, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - The "Gravellotte" Rhapsody, typescript essay (Box 2)
  - A Mirage, typescript story (Box 2)
  - The Explosion of Plato, typescript story (Box 2)
  - The Fatal Friend, typescript story (Box 2)
  - Hyacinth O'Hara typescript story (Box 2)
  - Keppler's Nude, typescript story (Box 2)
  - Thou Lovely One Far Distant by Ludwig Holstein, translation by CWS – typescript poem (Box 2)
  - The Key of Song, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - Chiquita, typescript poem (Box 2)
  - Misc. poems (Box 2)
  - Poetry CWS (Box 2)
  - Poetry CWS (Box 2)
  - The Old Mandarin by Christopher Mosley, review by CWS typescript (Box 2)
  - An Editor Looks at Poetry by Stanton A. Coblentz, review by CWS typescript (Box 2)
  - The Fall of the Magicians by Weldon Kees, review by CWS; typescript (Box 2)
  - The Wind That Shakes the Barley by James Barke, review by CWS typescript and holo. (Box 2)
  - The Future of Freedom in the Orient by Ralph Coniston, review by CWS – typescript (Box 2)
  - Back in High, holograph manuscript (Box 2)
  - April Violets by Hjalman Södenberg, translation by CWS typescript story (Box 2)
  - Fragment of play, typescript play (Box 2)
  - With the Current, holograph story (Box 2)
  - Sympathy by Telephone, typescript story (Box 2)
  - The Butterfly on the Mountain, typescript story (Box 2)
  - The Clown by Hjalman Södenberg, translation by CWS typescript story (Box 2)
  - With an Introduction, typescript essay (Box 2)
  - A Cup of Tea, typescript essay (Box 2)
  - The Parson's Cow by Hjalman Södenberg, translation by CWS typescript story (Box 2)
  - The Portrait by Hjalman Södenberg, translation by CWS typescript story (Box 2)
  - The Accomplished Dragon by Hjalman Södenberg, translation by CWS – typescript story (Box 2)
  - Churchyard Arabesque by Hjalman Södenberg, translation by CWS typescriptstory (Box 2)
  - T.S. Eliot Revises his Creed, typescript essay (Box 2)
  - Collected Lyrical poems by Vivian Locke Ellis, review by CWS typescript (Box 2)
  - The Image and the Law by Howard Nemerov, review by CWS holograph (Box 2)
  - I Am Aware of Cities, typescript poetry manuscript (Box 2)
  - Time Will Teil a Fantasy in Two Acts, typescript play (Box 2)
  - Toward an Honest Answer, typescript story (Box 2)
  - The Misconduct Mark by Hjalman Södenberg, translation by CWS typescript – story (Box 2)
  - The History Teacher by Hjalman Södenberg, translation by CWS typescript – story (Box 2)
  - The Patriarch Papinian, typescript story (Box 2)
  - The Darkness Gathers, typescript story (Box 2)
  - With the Current, typescript story (Box 2)
  - Preface and Contents of Södenberg Collection, holograph (Box 2)
  - April Violets by Hjalman Södenberg, translation by CWS holograph (Box 2)
  - Vox Populi by Hjalman Södenberg, translation by CWS typescript story (Box 2)
  - Fragments of play, typescript and holograph play (Box 2)
  - The Flower Seiler, typescript play (Box 2)
  - Susie's Grandmother, original typescript (Box 2)
  - Notebook, misc. reviews, plays, etc... (Box 2)
  - Translations – mostly Scandinavian (Box 3)
  - Misc. poems (Box 3)
  - Misc. fragments in envelope (Box 3)
  - Misc. essays, Reviews, and poems (Box 3)
  - Misc. writings (Box 3)
  - Misc. writings (Box 3)
  - Misc. writings (Box 3)
  - Misc. writings in envelope (Box 3)
  - Misc. writings in envelope (Box 3)
  - Misc. writings (Box 3)
  - Voices in the Canyon: A Dramatic Phantasy, typescript play (Box 3)
  - Voices in the Canyon – copy with note (Box 3)
  - The Stars Above, holograph play (Box 3)
  - The Stars Above, complete bound copy (Box 3)
  - The Stars Above – incomplete copy (Box 3)
  - The Deathless Don, typescript play (Box 3)
  - Lotus Island, typescript play (Box 3)
  - Lotus Island, holograph play (Box 3)
  - Fragment of a Story (Box 3)
  - Voices in the Canyon, typescript play (Box 3)
  - The Stars Above, typescript play (Box 3)
  - The Message of April, typescript play (Box 3)
  - Fragment of Galley Proof (Box 3)
  - Voices in the Canyon, typescript and holograph play (Box 3)
  - Sea and Bay, typescript poem (Box 3)
  - Masks Off, typescript play (Box 3)
  - Masks Off, typescript play (Box 3)
  - Misc. Poetry, typescript poems (Box 3)
  - Misc. Poetry, typescript poems (Box 3)
  - Susie's Folks, typescript play (Box 3)
  - Gustaf Fröding: Sweden's Greatest Lyric Poet, typescript and holograph essay (Box 3)
  - Misc. Hjalman Södenberg Stories, typescript stories (Box 3)
  - Misc. writings, typescript and holograph (Box 3)
  - Misc. writings, typescript and holograph (Box 3)
  - Misc. Poetry, typescript and holograph (Box 3)
  - Misc. Poetry, typescript and holograph (Box 3)
  - The Discarded Christmas Tree, typescript poem (Box 3)
  - Misc. poems (Box 3)
  - Aunt Elsbettel (Box 4)
  - Misc. plays, mostly holograph (Box 4)
  - Lighthouse Ledge, typescript story (Box 4)
  - Misc. writings, typescript (Box 4)
  - Getting Together (Box 4)
  - Athens was his Mistress (Box 4)
  - The Hell-Fire Club, typescript story (Box 4)
  - Two Bond Salesmen, carbon typescript story (Box 4)
  - Her Son's Room, typescript story (Box 4)
  - Danger Past: A Prose Idyll, typescript story (Box 4)
  - Robert Norwood: A Pastor Poet in Philadelphia, typescript essay (Box 4)
  - Editing a Poetry Magazine, typescript essay (Box 4)
  - Thomas Hardy: The Greatest Living Writer of English, typescript essay (Box 4)
  - Misc. writings and fragments (Box 4)
  - Nationalism in Swedish Poetry, typescript essay (Box 4)
  - Gustaf Fröding, Swedish Lyric Poet, typescript essay (Box 4)
  - ls Our Time Lacking in Literary Productivity?, typescript essay (Box 4)
  - The National Poet of Finland: Johan Ludvig Runeberg, typescript essay (Box 4)
  - The National Poet of Sweden: Verner Von Heidenstam, Winner of the Nobel (Box 4)
  - Needed, typescript story (Box 4)
  - Misc. writings and fragments (Box 4)
  - On a Common Mussel Shell, holograph poem (Box 4)
  - Misc. fragments, holograph (Box 4)
  - A Daughter of Boston, typescript manuscript in brown envelope (Box 4)
  - Misc. fragments, holograph (Box 4)
  - A Daughter of Boston (Box 4)
  - Misc. writings and fragments, holograph (Box 4)
  - Misc. writings, holograph (Box 4)
  - Fragments (Box 4)
  - The Code of Munich, holograph essay (Box 4)
  - People and Personages, typescript and holograph poem in brown envelope (Box 4)
  - Misc. writings and fragments (Box 4)
  - Misc. Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Misc. writings (Box 4)
  - Misc. writings in envelope (Box 4)
  - Misc. writings in envelope (Box 4)
  - Misc. writings (Box 4)
  - Misc. Poetry (Box 4)
  - Fragment of a play, typescript (Box 4)
  - Sunset Harbor (Box 4)
  - Unidentified play (Box 4)
  - A Tutor at Surfside, typescript/manuscript (Box 4)
  - Four Kisses, typescript/manuscript (Box 4)
  - Misc. Reviews by CWS (Box 4)
  - A Little Book by a Big Man: Review of Adventure and Other Papers by (Box 4)
  - Poetry, Imported and Domestic, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - From Both Sides of the Pond, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Novices and Masters, review by CWS holograph (Box 4)
  - Spring Harvest of Verse, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - A Selection from Modern Swedish Poetry, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Poems of Places, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - A Syrian Humanist, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Recent Books of Verse, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Life and Lyricism, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Books Worth Nothing, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Song and Celebration, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Recent Verse, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Experiment and Mastery, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - An Eastern Western Poet, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Verse Diversified, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Modern Realism with and OId Norse Background, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Recent Verse, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - Books Worth Nothing, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - The Romance of Duty, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - A Sea Hamsun, review by CWS typescript (Box 4)
  - A Thoughtful Experiment in Verse by CWS (Box 4)
  - Poems – Loose (Box 5)
  - Jane Pratt: Counsellor at Love: The Chalmers Case, typescript story (Box 4)
  - Before Love: A Portrait in Comedy, typescript play (Box 5)
  - Falstaff an Broadway, typescript play (Box 5)
  - Tristan the Nero, typescript play in binder (Box 5)